PITTSBURGH, 1999
Good evening. At the tone,
the time will be 4:53 and 50 seconds.
the time will be 4:53 and 59 seconds.
Hey, munchkin.
Turn it off.
You go to school?
I got back a while ago.
Good girl.
I have to make dinner.
You have to eat dinner.
I ate, Mom.
Good girl.
I have to...
I have to.
Gemma!
Please!
Gemmal
Mom?
Get away from me!
Watch me.
Mom!
Please!
You survived.
You see? Not as scary as I look.
They'll call you right back.
-Here you go.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you
Okay, come on. Let's go
Hey. Catch.
-Nice. Good squish
See you, Maya!
-Bye, Maya. See you tomorrow.
-Bye.
Mom?
I've been thinking.
Maybe we could give away some of my toys.
Really?
Just a few.
What, you turn nine
and suddenly toys aren't cool?
Never mind. We don't have to.
No. No, of course you can, honey.
If that's what you want.
Everyone else voted for Alex because he
said he'd bring M&M's to school every day.
antrinake-evervone lojlow
You-can't just say things
and make everyone follow you around.
It's not fair.
Radar!
kiddo
Hey
gosh. She will
not stop asking me for a dog
Please?
It's all right
Your mom will come around
-Not helping
Come on
Bye, Radar.
-What do you want for dinner?
-Lasagna?
Lasagna? Okay. You gonna help?
Sure.
Yeah? Good job.
How was school, sweetheart?
Mr. and Mrs. Sullivan. It was good
She reminds me of someone
wasn't talking to you at all, Bill.
wasn't talking to you at all, Bill
haven't been for 40 years
-Cute bunny?
-No.
-Pink Booger?
-Nah!
What? We gotta keep that one.
What about Grizz?
-Sorry.
-Sorry, bud.
What about her?
-What was her name? Baby Hildy?
No
Throw her in the box.
You are having way too much fun with this.
-This one?
-Keep.
-This one, you want?
Well, hello there.
-Well, hello there.
I was thinking, like, Goodwill?
Well, just in case we change our minds.
Okay, but we won't.
You know about dumpsters, right?
Why don't you get ready for bed,
smarty-pants?
Is this my grandma?
Let's put that away.
She looks nice.
Why can't we ever talk about her?
When you're older.
"Ingrid." Did she get in trouble?
Something like that.
She had cool jewelry.
Come on.
It's cold in here. Go.
Maya?
God.
Good evening.
At the tone, the time will be..
Maya?
...4:53 and 50 seconds
Good evening
At the tone, the time will be.
At the tone, the time will be..
I can't do ths mymore
The door is open.
Gemma..
Gemma, please.
Gemma.
Don't leave me here.
Please. Come, come closer.
Please help me. Help me.
Please. Please, Gemma. Please.
Gemma... Open the door.
I need you. I need you.
Please open the door, Gemma.
Please help me.
Please help me. Gemma, please.
Gem-
Watch me.
Mom!
You okay?
Shit.
I am so sorry. Sorry, baby.
You're not supposed to say "shit."
Nothing gets past you, does it?
You having a nightmare?
How'd you know?
You were screaming.
Really?
That must've been kinda scary, huh?
Did you find this in the garage?
Are you sure?
I-I lost this
exact flashlight when I was a kid.
You're weird.
Let's go.
Radar!
-Morning
Come here!
Sorry, Radar. I gotta get to school
Hey! What has gotten into you?
Sorry.
Sorry about him!
Who are they?
Just some people getting their steps in.
Come on We're late.
Make sure you floss
behind the molars, too.
What?
I've flossed more in the last year
than I have in my whole life.
Well, it has made your mouth
infinitely more kissable.
Really? I wouldn't know.
The only way I get to see my girifriend
is if.I go to the dentist,
and there, she just means business.
Okay. I'm just saying.
Well, we could go out next week.
just gotta get Liz to babysit Maya.
Or I could cook you and Maya
dinner at your place.
And then you don't need a babysitter.
You don't have to do that.
I think things are pretty great like this
Do you just not want me to meet her?
Nick, I do...
when the time is right.
She's just never had a guy in the picture
And look at that.
No more cavities.
Gemma.
hat? What is it?
You okay?
Just dizzy or something
Didn't sleep so good last night.
Bad dream?
Yeah.
What was it about?
My mom.
Shit.
I'm sorry.
She looked how she was at the end.
Evil.
Look, I just... I don't know
how you stay in that house.
Well, it's a perfectly good house.
And I inherited it
I'm just saying, you know,
you're a lot braver than I am
If that crazy shit would
have happened to me as a kid,
would ve sold the house.
wouldve torn it down.
I am never letting go of that house.
am making it a home that I never had.
-Did you brush your teeth?
-Yes.
-With toothpaste?
-Yes, Mom.
Can I play in my pillow fort?
Come on. Get some rest.
-Love you
-I love you.
Love you.
Okay.
Maya?
Come on.
Gotcha!
Maya?
No!
Maya!
No. No, no.
He's coming.
Mom?
What are you doing?
Sorry, honey.
Just cleaning up.
It's the middle of the night.
Come on.
Let's get you back to bed.
Come on. That's it. Good job. Come on.
Let's go to bed. Yeah.
Okay, well, did you lock up last night?
I think so.
Okay. Then maybe Maya grabbed it
from the garage and brought it inside.
No. No, no, no, no.
This came from those creepy old people.
Old people?
But you said you didn't see them.
I did... in my sleep.
Okay, look, if these nightmares
keep happening,
maybe you gotta talk with someone
about what's causing 'em.
No. I don't need anybody.
Oh, no. I know.
I'm just saying, if you ever do,
it'll be okay.
Be nice, even.
-Shit.
-What?
Goddamn it.
Just dealing with
my own nightmares over here.
Hey, Tony! Need you to take over.
I woke up with the same kind of jewelry
my mom had.
Tell me how that makes sense
Gem, if you keep yourself in that house
with all those memories,
they're bound to seep in sometimes.
Gemma.
Sorry.
What happened?
Maybe the cleaning guy broke it.
Come on, we got a full house.
-Here you go.
-Thanks.
Lester?
How are you doing today?
I know this is weird, but I..
I think I've seen you
walking in my neighborhood.
You were with those two ladies.
All right.
Jesus, your molars are rotting
When was the last time you had X-rays?
Bite down.
I'm just gonna take a look inside, okay?
Where's my toy?
Stay.
No.
No. No.
You can have her when she's dead.
No.
Time for a test.
Eeny...
meeny...
miny...
moe.
You have to go.
Who are you?
Come find me on the material plane.
Get back to your body
before it's too late.
-Thank you.
-It's what I do.
Will you check my homework?
Mom?
Hey.
Hey, let's.. let's eat.
We... We have to eat dinner.
We already ate.
Right.
Mom, the police are outside.
I know it was here.
I like your slippers.
Thank you.
I've heard a lot about you.
That you're getting
really good grades at school.
And that you love dogs.
And you make kick-ass pillow forts.
You're not supposled to say "kick-ass.
Shit.
I mean, shoot. Yeah, shoot.
I just saw it. I thought it was here.
I know it was here.
Is my mom okay?
Have you seen my other shoe, honey?
No.
She's so cool.
I... I'll be back in...
I don't know. But just call me
if she needs anything?
Like, anything.
-Okay.
-Bye.
Wait, you're gonna tell me
where you're going, at least?
I'm going to find someone
I met in a dream.
Hi.
Hello. I'm looking for someone.
I think she wanted me to come here.
people used to pragtice on pigskin.
but really, it's too thick.
Grapefruit skin's just like ours.
It's taut.
It's easy to tear if you mess up.
Sorry, but she gave me this.
Elise told me you'd be coming.
Where is she?
She doesn't even know where you are?
Oh, boy.
I can't hear her respond either,
not really.
I can't hear her cespond either,
notreally.
Most of the time, she sends me images
that I have to interpret.
Like this.
I don't understand. Where is Elise ?
She dies in 2011.
She lives in the further now.
Okay, so this music is gonna
put me into a trancelike sleep
I'll still be here physically,
but the consciousness that speaks to you,
that'll be Elise.
As soon as this rings,
I want you to take off the headphones.
Too long in there and other spirits
can start smelling my presence.
What is this for?
In case you screw it up
and let another spirit get inside my body.
Can I get a little help?
So, I just press play?
Remember:
that timer rings,
you take these off my ears.
Okay.
HealingGal
Healing Wait.
Do it.
Healing
Clare?
Hello, Gemma.
My name is Elise.
Okay, Elise.
I need help
I am having these dark and intense dreams.
I'm losing track of time.
I am scaring my daughter.
I need someone to tell me
how to stop this.
I can help you.
But first, you have to understand..
those are not dreams, Gemma.
You are a Traveler.
A what?
You have the ability to travel
into a place called the Further,
the dark void between
this world and the next one.
Gemma...
You're seeing the dead.
Is this some kind of a joke?
Every Traveler questions it at first.
There was a family I once helped,
the Lamberts.
It took them a long time
to understand the danger they were in.
A couple of weeks ago, they finally
closed the door on their demons for good.
But when one door closes in the Further...
another one opens.
And behind that new door
is something terrible.
A very powerful entity
who has been locked away for a long time.
And he's coming for you, Gemma.
He has discovered that you have
a very rare, very special gift.
You can bring things from the spirit world
into the living world in physical form.
So you are not just a Traveler, Gemma.
You are what I call a Courier.
You can bring things back and forth.
This entity plans to grab hold of you
while you're in the Further
and hitchhike back to your world.
I've seen it.
I can't control when I go to that place.
It's like I'm being dragged there.
That's because he has help.
Those psychos who have been following me.
His Acolytes.
They're unnatural Travelers.
They use a sedative to force
their way into the Further.
You're doing that, Gemma.
The more fury you feel,
the stronger your power gets.
You have to figure out how
to protect yourself from the Acolytes.
Every time you come in contact with them,
they're wearing you down...
Elise?
I just want him to leave me alone!
He won't leave you alone.
He's awakening your power.
The more they wear you down,
the easier you'll slip into the Further.
More.
Once he's back in your world,
he'll make you bring others.
Many others.
More.
This entity has promised freedom
to anyone stuck in the Further.
But your gift.
Mom?
...takes the ultimate toll.
Mom!
I've never seen a future like that.
are gonna take over the world?
Okay. So she told you demons
She didn't just tell me. It was a vision.
I saw it.
I saw you all die.
Maya, everyone.
These things are gonna come true
if I can't find a way to stop it.
Nick.
Yeah. Sorry, I was just processing.
These people, they know where I live.
They know where I work.
The old man, he came in for a cleaning.
And guess what?
Two sets of teeth.
They're just
always walking around out there.
We just need to get ahold
of that gas tank that they drag around.
I think it's...
I think it's a sedative
that they're using to get into my dreams.
No... No. Gem, we cannot just
cut off some old people's oxygen..
Well, then freaking tase them or whatever.
I thought you wanted to be needed.
Okay.
Nick...
No, it's fine.
You're just clearly... Yeah.
What?
You're just not yourself right now.
Like...
am my mother.
No, that's not what I'm thinking at all.
Okay, listen.
If they know where you live,
I can have a unit parked out there
all day and night to scare them off.
I just got to get you a different place
to go to sleep.
I gotta get you out of this house.
Would you stop it about the house?
It is not the house that is haunted.
It is me!
Okay. Hey. Hey.
Then I'll stay up.
All night, okay?
And I'll wake you
to make sure that you're okay.
And if those three show up, I'll cuff 'em.
Okay?
Mom?
I see you're sleeping.
Hello?
Maya?
No.
Time to finish the test.
Mom?
No.
No. No! No!
Hey.
You okay?
I know where it is.
You know where what is?
The door.
Okay.
You know where the door is.
That's... That's good.
-Hey!
-Oh, my God.
What the fuck?
Stay here. Stay here.
What the hell is that?
She's almost ready.
Now get back to the Sullivans'.
Mom?
One second.
One second, sweetie.
What's going on?
You okay?
I saw those old people.
They're in the Sullivans' house.
What?
When?
Just now.
-Can I sleep in here?
-No. Not tonight.
Come on.
Okay. Just stay in bed.
I have to...
That's it. I'm bringing them in.
No. It doesn't matter
if they're locked up.
They can still get me when they're asleep.
They're gonna keep trying
until I can bring one back alive.
Well, great. That's great.
This fridge probably holds two bodies max.
We have to stop them from traveling.
Police
Open up.
Hi, I am Officer Mendoza.
We got a call to do a wellness check
on Mr. and Mrs. Sullivan.
Wanna come out here?
Ask you a few questions?
Okay...
need backup at 1241 Maple Grove Lane.
Okay. First off,
how do you know the Sullivans?
OLI
You've heard the truth that I know
how to walk in the invisible realm.
You offer me your devotion.
Mrs. Sullivan?
I offer you a way to see your ancestors
and loved ones again.
I commune with them.
And I'll teach you to do the same.
When the world understands
there is life after death...
...everything will change.
You three.
you have such a simple job.
Help me to the other side.
When's the last time
you've seen the Sullivans?
Can you tell me that, at least?
Take away the fear of dying,
nobody needs to hold back.
-What the...
-No rules, no restraint.
Just pure desire.
Now...
put yourselves somewhere dark.
A calm mind helps ease the transition.
Let go as you sleep.
Let go.
Gemma.
You're not alone in here.
Gemma...
You're surrounded by the dead.
..to kill you.
I promised them a way out.
to hurt you... to kill you.
Stop following me!
Gemma.
Hey. It's me. It's me. It's me.
It's me.
saw him.
I saw him. He... He spoke to me. He..
He was on the TV. He...
He...
I took it to the Further.
Holy shit.
What else can you make disappear?
Okay. I got you.
I got you.
Mom?
You coming downstairs soon?
Get away from me!
So, this guy was killing people
to prove to their loved ones
he could talk to them after they died.
Got a bunch of people to follow him.
Guess that's one way to use your gift.
Yep. The arrest, it went sideways,
and he got shot and killed
in front of his followers.
Some of them never stopped following him.
Okay. Elise has a lot to say.
They've done enough tests now.
They're gonna go through
with their plan tonight.
So, while Gemma is in her bedroom asleep,
they're gonna rip her
out of her physical body.
They're gonna take her astral body
to Cyrus, wherever he's waiting,
and he's gonna latch on.
Then they're gonna bring Gemma's
astral body back to her physical body,
and when she wakes up,
he'll be in our world.
But we're not gonna
let that happen, right?
Nick. We're not.
We are gonna put him
right back where he came from.
And you're gonna be the bait.
You're gonna go into the Further
to meet Elise, Further
and the two of you are gonna
lead Cyrus to that red door.
Now the only problem is,
ever since your little break-in,
the Acolytes have been in the Further
guarding that red door 24/7.
So, Nick, this is where
you come into play.
The Acolytes' physical bodies
are in that house across the street.
They're gonna be using their sedatives.
you're gonna break in,
you're gonna kill the gas,
and you're gonna wake them up.
Which means that Gemma and Elise
can get into the red door. Elise
Cyrus is gonna follow you right in.
What's inside?
Elise says that every door is different.
Some of them hide demons.
Some of them hide memories of the dead.
But once you're inside,
you gotta keep going.
All right? You go deep enough
that he loses track of you.
But you have something yrus doesn't:
a way home.
I'm gonna guide you with my voice
back through the Further.
And then you're gonna
lock that door behind you,
and you're gonna get back
to your physical body.
And then we aget to
go back to our nom ves
Normal sounds nice
We get through tonight,
and Maya gets her mom back.
You know how sometimes
you get a toothache,
you have to come see me at work?
Sometimes, people get aches
in other places.
People can get sicknesses
in their heads too.
And it can make them mean and scary and..
My mom was like that.
I grew up terrified of her.
I hate that she's a part of me.
And I think maybe that's.
I think that's why I keep
all of her stuff,
just to remind myself
of who I never want to become.
Listen to me.
I am doing everything that I can
to make sure that you're
never scared of me again, okay?
Can I just go in?
Yeah.
Hey.
There she is.
Why don't you head on in,
get him some treats?
Thank you.
Oh, my gosh. Of course. Don't mention it.
You got big plans tonight?
Yeah.
Yeah, I do.
I love you, Maya.
Okay.
You have to clear your mind
and focus on the music.
It'll help you fall asleep.
So, why are you helping Elise?
You must have a good reason
to go through all this.
My mom died in childbirth,
and I was put up for adoption.
I never even knew what she looked like.
You ready?
Okay, deep breaths.
I'm going in.
Shit.
It's not working.
Are you ready?
They're still here.
Oh, shit.
Hey, they killed the Sullivans.
Nick, just find them and get out of there.
Come on, Nick.
Gemma!
Elise!
Got the ladies.
Well, wake those bitches up.
No!
Come on. Hey. Come on.
Wake up! Wake up.
Got one of 'em.
Okay. Done.
Hey.
Shit.
Nick, what's the status on number three?
Working on it.
We have to go now.
Come on, Gemma.
Lead Cyrus in.
I know this place.
What is this?
Memories.
Mine?
Your mom's.
No, no, no, no, no.
Gemma?
You home, munchkin?
I have to make dinner.
You have to eat dinner.
I ate, Mom.
Please.
Get away from me!
He came after her first.
No, please.
Please.
She's so scared.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
You just let yourself sleep,
and then we'll wake up together.
Wherever you go, I go.
She was a Courier too.
But if you won't bring me back.
I'll make her do it.
You can't stop this.
Watch me.
No.
No!
Wait!
Mom!
No!
She locked him away in her memory.
She was protecting me.
I hated her.
She protected me, and I hated her.
Mom?
Hey, munchkin.
All these years...
you were trapped here with him?
Gemma.
Can we get her out of here?
If she had this gift, and you have it...
It's inherited.
It's not possible.
Oh, no! Jump!
Mom!
Mom! Mom!
Maya!
-They weren't just wearing you down.
-They were wearing Maya down too.
Get away from me!
-No.
-Nick has to wake up the third one now.
No! No!
Nick? We're out of time.
Where is the last place
they'd think anyone would look?
Clare, guide us home.
Gemma. Gemma, follow my voice.
Follow my voice.
Follow my voice, Gemma.
Oh, come on.
Okay.
Wake up. Wake up. Wake up. Come on.
Come on! Come on!
-My radiant child.
-No, no.
Let me breathe the air again.
No. No.
Wake up!
All you have to do..
is wake up.
You okay, kiddo?
He's out.
No.
Maya.
Follow my voice.
Come on, Gemma! Come home!
Screw this. I'm going to her.
Maya!
Come on.
It's okay. It's okay. It's okay.
Where's Maya? What did you do with her?
Get on the ground!
Now!
No, Nick. Don't...
What the hell?
No.
Let me go!
Maya!
Oh, my God.
Gemma, come home.
Stay.
Now...
the dead shall rise.
Sleep.
Have her.
No! No!
No.
Again.
Maya?
Maya!
Mom!
Again.
They're passing through to your world.
Cyrus still has help
Clare!
Has Nick found the last Acolyte?
Has Nick found
Has Nick found the laist Aco lyte?
Has Nick found the las
Nick's not responding.
Listen to me.
Only you can end this now.
Wait, you're not coming?
I have to help Nick wake the last one.
Get to your body.
And then what?
You can bring things back.
Clear your mind
and you can bring
anything back to the Further.
But Maya doesn't have much time.
I will make sure your mom gets to
where she's going at the end of all this.
Now go.
Go save your daughter.
They're everywhere.
-You have to go.
-No. No, no, no. No.
-No.
-Trust me.
-I'm not leaving you.
-Please. Help Nick.
I got Maya.
I have a plan.
Get it. I get it.
Who's that? I want her.
No, I want her.
She's mine!
No!
I want her!
Maya!
Mom?
No, no.
Maya!
Bring her to me.
Go back to the real world.
Let my voice be your guide.
Keep a steady stride.
Wake up, you son of a bitch.
Wake up!
Nick, come on. Wake up.
Wake up. Nick.
No. No. No.
You're supposed to be on the other side.
Get me more followers.
She still has a few more to give
before she dies.
No!
Maya! Maya!
Maya!
Get off....
Get away from her!
That was just the beginning.
Maya! No!
What are you doing?
I'm helping her.
It's what I do.
Mom! Mom!
Thanks for the ride.
No, no.
You had such a simple job.
Mom! Mom!
Mom!
So much death is coming.
-Maya!
Mom!
Mom! No! No!
Now your daughter will watch you die.
No!
It's okay, sweetie.
It's okay.
Just let go.
Let go.
Now we rip apart your world.
But we're not in my world.
We're in yours.
Holy shit.
She took it to the Further.
No.
Wait!
Mom !
No!
Mom. Mom.
Oops !
Looks like you broke your promise.
Wait.
Bye, munchkin.
Hey.
Hey, sweetie.
You're back.
I'm back.
You were so brave.
You saved me.
It runs in the family.